CONTACT



Phone

+447446223855



🖾 Email

Jamshed.habibi100@gmail.com



Address

London, United Kingdom W12

OTHER



Website

jamshedhabibi.netlify.com



In LinkedIn

linkedin.com/jamshed-habibi



Github

github.com/JamshedHabibi

SKILLS

- **JavaScript**
- React & Context API
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Styled-Components
- **Bootstrap**
- **JQuery**
- **NodeJS**
- Version Control (.Git)
- Continuous Integration (Netlify)
- Jest
- Russian (Native)

INTERESTS

- Travelling
- Fitness Enthusiast
- FreeCodeCamp Meetups

Jamshed Habibi

SUMMARY

I am a graduate software developer, self-taught and proficient in JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS/Styled-Components, Bootstrap, NodeJS and Git. I have experience in test driven development, using Jest, and I am comfortable with Agile development practises. I also have a good understanding of object-orientated programming.

EDUCATION

University of Birmingham

September 2016 - July 2019

- BEng Mechanical Engineering Grade: First Class Honours
- Relevant Modules: Computing (84%), Mechatronics (71%), Control Engineering (75%)
- Mechanical Engineering Department Student Representative

Ark Putney Academy

September 2008 - June 2016

- A-Levels: Mathematics (A), Further Mathematics (B), Physics (B)
- GCSE's 11 A*-C: Mathematics (A), Statistics (A), Physics (A), Chemistry (B), Biology (B), English (B),
- Sixth Form Senior Prefect & Team Leader.
- Award received for exemplary contribution to mathematics department.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Technology Systems Operator/Analyst, Hawk-Eye Innovations

June 2018 - October 2018

- Successfully operated goal line technology in 25+ football matches, earning the responsibility to manage a rig day by myself.
- Harvesting best practises from unrelated industries, I troubleshooted both hardware and software issues under immense time pressure, looking at the root of the problem and systematically eliminating potential causes. As a result, I prevented 100% of critical errors which allowed goal-line technology to operate effortlessly at crucial times.
- Routinely passed relentless UEFA accuracy checks for goal-line technology to 1mm accuracy, ensuring highly reliable delivery of the system, at the same time managing very high client expectation for repeat
- Provided additional analyst services to premier league teams, retrieving feeds from TV to put together a highlights package for teams to effectively review their players performance. Proving incredibly useful, we have negotiated new contracts with Manchester City and Southampton.
- One of few employees in the company building computational offside model points, using specialized software, which are flourishing in 100's of VAR-operated games.

RECENT PROJECTS

Real Estate Application (jamsheds-real-estate.netlify.com)

December 2019

- Developed a web application, using React & JavaScript that allows users to effortlessly search for properties in London and filter the properties to select their ideal home.
- Powered by Nestoria REST API, creating real time updates to properties on the market.
- React Context API was utilised, allowing the fetched property data to be stored readily in a state and easily read across all components. This way, any changes made to one webpage can be read across to other webpages.

E-Commerce Bike Shop (jamsheds-ebike-shop.netlify.com)

October 2019

- Created a full e-commerce experience where customers can virtually purchase electric bikes and accessories, applying a sandbox PayPal Express Checkout API.
- Built with React, permitting better, responsive web performance from its ability to reduce rendering time by writing to virtual DOM components before being sent to the HTML DOM.
- Implemented Google Maps API, providing location services for customers, at the same time restricting the API Key to prevent use of API in unknown domains.
- Use of Styled-Components, allowing for effective and time-saving reusable design components to be used across all components of the app.
- Utilised Bootstrap to create a responsive webpage. Customers can easily browse the application in different screen-resolutions and mobile-mode.

Portfolio Website (jamshedhabibi.netlify.com)

September 2019 - Present

- Built with React to utilise the JSX syntax, as it allows easy HTML/JQuery quoting within the JavaScript functions
- Applied CSS & Bootstrap, to allow for well structured, in-depth designs for each component. Also utilised CSS media queries to create a responsive webpage for use in different screen-resolutions and mobile use.
- JQuery to implement a functional navigation menu and arrow buttons by providing a smooth scrolling feature, resulting in improved UX.

Registration Form (jamsheds-registration-form.netlify.com)

August 2019

- Built an interactive registration form with vanilla JavaScript, HTML & CSS.
- Consists of email, username & password data input, which depending on the input will allow you to progress with the form. This is indicated by cool animations, such as a progress bar and error/success screen flash.